Hello and welcome back. Let us now talk about Video Inpainting.
【未完成版本】 大家好 欢迎回来 今天我们来讨论视频修复
You basically already have all the tools to do Video Inpainting.
基本上 你们已经掌握了视频修复的所有工具
Remember, and I'm showing these in very slow motion, a video is a sequence of
现在我用慢镜头播放这个视频 记住 视频其实就是
frames, a sequence of images. So, we can basically use the tools that
一系列的帧  (frame)  每一帧都是一幅图  因此 我们可以将
we developed for Image Inpainting now in Video Inpainting.
图像修复中的工具运用到视频修复来
How? For example, we can take, in the Cut and
怎么做呢？ 举个例子 在剪切和粘贴操作中
Paste, instead of two-dimensional patches x, y, we can consider three-dimensional
这一次不是二维空间中修补xy平面 我们考虑的是在三维空间中
patches x, y, t and look at them in the video.
修补x y t三个维度 考虑到整个视频
In the whole video, that would be very expensive but we can look at them in
这样的修补开销很大 但是我们可以只考虑
segments of the video. We can also run the partial differential
视频中的片段 我们也可以利用偏微分方程
equations or the variational formulations considering, for example,
或变分方程 比如说
three-dimensional gradients. When we talk about curvature, we can
求三维梯度 涉及曲率的时候
consider the videos as surfaces and talk about surface curvatures like Mean
我们可以把视频当作曲面 然后讨论曲面曲率
curvature or Gaussian curvature. So basically, the same type of concepts,
比如平均曲率或高斯曲率 所以说 这是同样的概念
Laplacian, we can take derivatives in the x, y, and t directions.
比如拉普拉斯算子 求x y t方向上的导数
Some type of concepts, we can expand to do Video Inpainting.
同样的概念 可以拓展到视频修复中
And that's how today, Video Inpainting is done in the literature extending those
而如今 有关视频修复的文献做的就是
concepts that we saw for images. Now, Video Inpainting has a bit of
拓展图像中已知的概念 视频修复也有一些
different characteristics. For example,
不同于图像修复的特点 比如说
here, let me just show you with the arrows.
这里 让我用箭头标示出来
There are some objects that are static in the video so they will never appear in
视频有一些物体是静止的 所以它们的背景不会出现在任何帧当中
any of the frames. And there are some objects that move in
视频中也有一些物体是运动的
the video so it's slightly different if we want to remove static objects than if
如果我们想要移除静止的物体 就会和移除动态物体有些不同
we want to remove moving objects. For example, if we want to remove a
举个例子 如果我们想要移除一个运动的物体
moving object, all what we have to do is wait until it's gone in one of the future
我们要做的是 等到在未来某一帧中这个物体消失了
frames and copy from those frames into the current frame.
然后把这些帧的相应区域复制到当前帧中
So, I want to remove this now. Look at my pointer, now it's gone.
我想移除这个物体 看向我的指针 现在它消失了
So, I basically can copy those pixels, those pixels from future frames into the
因此我可以在稍后的帧中把这些像素
current frame. Because the object is moving, the current background appears in
复制到当前帧 因为物体正在运动 当前的背景会出现在
some of the previous or some of the future frames.
之前或者之后的某些帧中
When the object is fixed, it's slightly different.
当物体是固定的 这会有些不同
The background is never revealed but this Cut and Paste or partial differential
它的背景并没有出现过 但是剪切粘贴或偏微分方程
equations or variation of formulations will work there.
或者变分方程仍然有效
So, you could if you want make a distinction between these two and
因此 如果你想区分处理这两者
differently inpaint each region or you could just let those techniques that we
你可以在每个区域用不同的修补方法 或者不区分
described for images work with all the objects.
对所有物体都运用这些在图像处理中讨论过的技术
Here, we see an example of this video inpainted with those combination of Cut
这里我们可以看到视频修复的一个例子
and Paste propagation of information as we have seen, we basically have removed a
其中结合了之前见过的剪切粘贴和信息传递
number of objects, we have removed basically this, this, and this. We have
我们移除了一些物体 移除了这个 这个 和这个物体
removed both static and dynamic objects with those techniques without making any
我们利用这些技术 不加区分地移除了静态的和动态的物体
explicit distinction between them. Here is another example.
这里有一个例子
what we want to remove now, as you see, is this object.
如你所见 现在我们想要移除这个物体
Remember, for inpainting you get the video,
记住 视频修复 和图像修复一样
as we got the image, you have to get the mask, a video with the mask.
你必须找到一个掩模 一个视频掩模
Now, of course, doing that by hand for video is much more time-consuming than
当然 手动寻找视频掩模比在静止图像中更加花时间
doing it by hand for still images. But we have to mix to do segmentation in
不过我们还必须同时进行视频分割 正如之前讨论的
video as we have seen, for example, the Roto Brush in Adobe's After Effects.
比如 Adobe After Effects中的Roto Brush
And here is the, the result of basically removing this person or this mask.
这里就是移除人物或者说移除掩模后的结果
And you see the video looks completely natural.
你看 这个视频看起来很自然
We, it's very hard to realize for us that this is not the original video but it
我们很难意识到 这并不是原始视频
actually is not and it's actually inpainted with this dynamic object.
但这确实不是 它对这个动态物体进行了修补
And now here, we have a second example. This is an example that we have already
现在 我们还有第二个例子 是之前我们见过的
seen in the past and once again, we are basically removing one object and making
再次 我们移除一个物体
you believe that it was the original video.
而且让你相信这是原始视频
This basically concludes our presentation of Image and Video Inpainting.
这下可以总结我们关于图像和视频修复的讨论了
We have seen very, very good techniques for doing this and as we talked in the
我们见到了用于修复的非常棒的技术 正如之前提到
past, this is used a lot, for example, in the movie industry.
这些技术运用广泛 比如 用于电影业
But its also used a lot to improve our own pictures, our own images, and remove
它也广泛用于改善我们的图像
objects that we don't like on those images.
可以移除图像中我们不喜欢的物体
I hope you had fun, this is really a fun topic.
希望大家学得愉快 这是一个非常有趣的话题
You can make a lot of nice stuff with Image and Video Inpainting.
你可以通过图像和视频修复制作许多漂亮的东西
Thank you very much and I am going to see you again next week.
非常感谢 下周再见
Thank you.
谢谢大家